ablewise.com 2007-12-12

# Privacy Policy

Terms Of Use  |  User Agreement  |  Privacy Policy  |  Prohibited and Restricted Items  |  **Ad Posting Tips** **  
 **

 **PRIVACY POLICY**

**SCOPE**

This Privacy Policy describes how we handle your personal information for our services on Ablewise.com. It applies generally to Ablewise.com website(s) and other related websites where this policy appears in the footer of the page ("the Sites"). Some Ablewise.com websites or websites we operate may be governed by separate privacy policies. The policy that applies on any of our domains or subdomains is always the policy that appears in the footer of each website.

By accepting the Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use in registration, you expressly consent to our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

**1\. COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

When you register with Ablewise.com, you provide us with personal information and consent to the transfer and storage of that information to our servers located in the United States.

We may collect and store the following personal information:

* email address, physical contact information, and sometimes financial information, such as credit card or bank account numbers;  
* community discussions, chats, dispute resolution, correspondence through the Site, and correspondence sent to us;  
* computer sign-on data, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the Site, and ad data;  
* other information, including IP address and standard web log information, and  
* supplemental information from third parties. (For example, if the information you provide cannot be verified, we may ask you to send us additional information (such as your driver license, credit card statement, and/or a recent utility bill or other information confirming your address), or to answer additional questions online to help verify your information.)  
* Please do not post any personal information on Ablewise.com's classifieds that you expect to keep private.

**2\. USAGE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience. You agree that we may use your personal information to:

* provide the services and customer support you request;  
* resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems;  
* prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce our Terms of Use;  
* customize, measure, and improve our services and the Sites' content and layout;

**3\. OUR DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We may disclose personal information to respond to legal requirements, enforce our policies, respond to claims that a listing or other content violates the rights of others, or protect anyone's rights, property, or safety.

We may also share your personal information with:

* service providers under contract who help with our business operations; (such as fraud investigations, bill collection, affiliate and rewards programs and co-branded credit cards)  
* other third parties to whom you explicitly ask us to send your information; (or about whom you are otherwise explicitly notified and consent to when using a specific service)  
* law enforcement or other governmental officials, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity; (In such events we will disclose name, city, state, telephone number, email address, User ID history, and fraud complaints.) and  
* other business entities, should we plan to merge with or be acquired by that business entity. (Should such a combination occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this privacy policy with respect to your personal information. If your personal information will be used contrary to this policy, you will receive prior notice.) 

**4\. ACTIVITY ASSOCIATED WITH USERNAME**

Your Username is displayed throughout Ablewise.com and is therefore available to the public. All of your activities on the Site will be traceable to your Username. Other people can see ads that you have posted, feedback, ratings and so on. Notices are sent to other community members regarding suspicious activity and policy violations on the Site and refer to Username(s) and specific items. Therefore, if you associate your name with your Username, the people to whom you have revealed your name to will be able to personally identify your Ablewise.com activities.

**5\. USING INFORMATION FROM ABLEWISE.COM**

Our Sites enable you to share personal information in order to complete transactions. We encourage you to disclose your privacy practices and respect the privacy of other users. We cannot guarantee the privacy or security of your information and therefore we encourage you to evaluate the privacy and security policies of your trading partner before entering into a transaction and choosing to share your information. To help protect your privacy, we allow only limited access to other users' contact(s). When users are involved in a transaction, they may have access to each other's name, User ID, email address, and other contact(s). In all cases, you must give other users a chance to remove themselves from your database and a chance to review what information you have collected about them.

You agree to use user information only for:

* Ablewise.com transaction-related purposes that are not unsolicited commercial messages;  
* using services offered through Ablewise.com (e.g. PM system and fraud complaints), or  
* other purposes that a user expressly chooses.

**6\. COOKIES**

We use "cookies" (small files placed on your hard drive) on certain pages of the Site to help analyze our web page flow, customize our services, measure promotional effectiveness, and promote trust and safety.

A few important things you should know about cookies are that:

* We offer certain features that are only available through the use of cookies.  
* We use cookies to help identify you and maintain your signed-in status.  
* Most cookies are "session cookies," meaning that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session.  
* You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although doing so may interfere with your use of the Sites.

**7\. NO SPAM, SPYWARE OR SPOOFING**

We and our users do not tolerate spam. Make sure to set your Ablewise.com notification preferences so we communicate to you as you prefer. You are not licensed to add other Ablewise.com users, even a user who has disclosed his/her contact(s) information you, to your mail list (email or physical mail) without their express consent. To report Ablewise.com related spam or spoof emails to Ablewise.com, please inform us via the Contact Us page. You may not use our communication tools to send spam or otherwise send content that would violate our Terms of Use. We do not rent or sell these email addresses.

**8\. ACCOUNT PROTECTION**

Use unique numbers, letters, and special characters for your Ablewise.com password and do not disclose it to anyone. If you do share your password or personal information with others, remember that you are responsible for all actions taken in the name of your account. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately notify Ablewise.com and change your password.

**9\. ACCESSING, REVIEWING AND CHANGING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

You can review and change most of your personal information by logging into the Site. Generally, we will not modify your personal information because it is very difficult to verify your identity remotely. You must promptly update your personal information if it changes or is inaccurate. Once you make a public posting, you may not be able to change or remove it. Upon your request, we will close your account and remove your personal information from view as soon as reasonably possible, based on your account activity and in accordance with applicable law. We do retain personal information from closed accounts in order to comply with law, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Use, and take other actions otherwise permitted by law.

**10\. SECURITY**

Your information is stored on our servers located in the United States. We treat data as an asset that must be protected and use lots of tools (encryption, passwords, physical security, etc.) to protect your personal information against unauthorized access and disclosure. However, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, and other users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from the Site. Therefore, although we work very hard to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private.

**11\. THIRD PARTIES**

Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document addresses only the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. If you disclose your information to others on the Internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them. Since Ablewise.com does not control the privacy policies of third parties, you are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties. We encourage you to find out more about the relevant third parties' policies before you disclose your personal information.

**12\. GENERAL**

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on the Site. All amended terms automatically take effect 30 days after they are initially posted on the Site. In addition, we will notify you in accordance with your Notification Preferences. Please direct all your questions to us via the Contact Us page.
